# Resumé - UI/UX & Graphic Designer | Peter Koenders

I'm a versatile UI/UX designer with over 20 years of all-round industry experience. I originally from a traditional Graphic Design and transitioned into Digital and Web Design. I have worked with small and large organisations. I am fastidious in work flow; definition and planning, research, design, technical, management and review.

- Implementation of the UI/UX design process
- · Estimating & proposal review
- · Iterative wire-framing, prototypes & design
- · Pattern libraries & style guides
- · HTML templates & components
- · Graphic design

I take an interest in and am an advocate for digital accessibility. I am also am curious and enjoy working with creative teams on diversified digital projects.

With professionalism, integrity and care, I work in a collaborative manner to plan, design and deliver crafted solutions with best practices in mind.



pkoenders@gmail.com



+64 2115 51085



https://pkoenders.netlify.app



https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-koenders



Westend, Palmerston North, 4410, New Zealand

# **Experiences**

# **Contractor - Designer**

Nov 2020 - Jan 2021

#### My Life My Voice

Working as a designer/developer for MLMV, I built a multilingual and accessible JAMstack website and progressive web app. I used Gatsby as the HTML/JS framework and used Sanity as a headless CMS. My developer and design skills evolved while using the React library.

# Responsibilities

#### Design

Design of web pages, journeys, components ensuring Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) 2.1 are adhered to.

#### **Development**

Used the JAMstack framework to build a serverless and Progressive Web App to deliver a locale multilingual experience (English, Māori + other) for users. Implemented the Sanity API to source content via GraphQL.

#### **Contractor & Volunteer** Jun 2019 - Aug 2020

# Sustainable Solutions, Muscular Dystrophy Association & Lynn Pronk

I have taken on contract and volunteer work on range of projects as a design professional and front-end developer to keep myself occupied and offering my skills where they can of use. Amongst these are the Muscular Dystrophy Association who are looking at an exciting opportunity to re-design their website which will include full web accessibility.

### **Design Lead - Contract**

Jun 2018 - Aug 2018

#### Vodafone, Auckland, New Zealand

In my role as a Design Lead working with the Content Team, I was accountable for a range of UI design tasks.

#### Responsibilities

# Digital brand update

Enhance portions of the Vodafone NZ public website and execute a digital brand update.

#### Design

Re-design web pages, journeys, components. Ensured brand guidelines are adhered to. Deliverables included design files and components, presented for a range of screen sizing and collaborate with stakeholders.

#### **Templates**

Created template designs and components to be consistent, work independently and together as a whole.

#### Pattern libraries & style guides

Designed, built and managed pattern libraries and style guides for design teams to use consistent components from a shared source.

#### **Senior Digital Designer**

2004 - 2018

#### Datacom Systems Limited, Auckland, New Zealand

In my role as a Senior Digital Designer in the Digital Experience Team, I grew and developed indispensable skills. I worked with multiple teams and environments. I was accountable for a range of UI/UX, graphic design tasks and had a hand in front-end development.

#### Responsibilities

#### Estimating and proposal review

Defined what efforts would be required for delivery. Review project plans and proposals and made suggestions where value could be added.

#### Design

Designer for a range of projects, both restrictive and customer facing. Deliverables included design files, templates and prototypes. Iterative wireframes to clarify screen requirements, elements/components and functionality. Explored flows, scenarios and created design options on analysis.

#### Pattern libraries & style guides

Designed, built and managed pattern libraries and style guides for design teams to use consistent components from a shared source.

## HTML prototypes

Created semantic and accessible HTML/SCSS prototypes and templates.

#### **Projects**

#### · Customer facing websites

At Datacom, I initially worked for Air New Zealand managing their CMS; designing and building homepage and landing page takeovers, updating content, integrating new designs and layouts. Other websites, which have since been updated; Bayleys, NZ Lotteries, Ballance, Spark and Fisher & Paykel Finance. Current websites include the HTML/CSS deliverables and translation to responsive design for Auckland Airports and UI/UX design and HTML/CSS deliverables for Aon Insurance.

#### · Micro-sites and module add-ons

Analysis, flow, wire-frame and design work for Chorus, Spark and Auckland Airports.

#### Web applications

UI/UX design and HTML deliverables for internal Cloud Services and Payroll applications. External application for Australian Red Cross Blood Service for their Organ Management System used by scientists and medical professionals.

#### Customer portals

UI design and HTML deliverables for Kotahi Logistics. A customer portal for container ordering, tracking and management.

#### Intranets

UI design and HTML deliverables for internal intranet for Datacom. UI Design for Bupa Health. Integration with Microsoft CRM and Salesforce.

#### · Graphic design

Create and manage print material for internal projects, prepared and composed collateral for internal and external research, analysis and sales presentations.

#### · Internal innovation hackfests

I participated in annual internal innovation hackfests. Made myself available as a design resource and mentorship of graduates.

#### **Achievements**

- I introduced HTML pattern libraries to assist integration teams implementing consistent components.
- · Delivery of accessible and functional HTML templates and prototypes for integration teams and

# Web & Print Designer 2001 - 2003

# London Centre of Contemporary Music, London, United Kingdom

The LCCM and the London College of Creative Media employed me to design their website. I also worked with their integration team to build their Student Management System. Other tasks I took on; design their identity logo, produce various print materials, course brochures, posters and stationery.

#### **Designer**

1996 - 2001

#### Contract UI Designer, London, United Kingdom

I worked for various design agencies across London in a variety of roles including; UI design for interactive TV, designer hand for Air New Zealand livery and British Telecom, where I was employed to design the UI for a child safe web browser.

# **Designer** 1993 - 1996

Designer, Megabyte/Terabyte, Auckland

Multimedia designer on a range of interactive projects.

# Education

**Web Accessibility** 

**Deque University** 

2021 - Present day

Recieved scholorship to participate in online digital accessibility courses.

Introduction to digital accessibility

Victoria University

2020

Exploring digital accessibility and what it takes to ensure online content is accessible.

Graded: A-

**Diploma of Computer Graphic Design**1992 - 1994

Whanganui School of Design, Whanganui, New Zealand

Three year Diploma of Computer Graphic Design.

Delivery of an interactive design and typography project for final year.

# **Interests**

Outside of my professional interests, caring for my children keeps me busy as a sole parent. I also muck in garden, make chili jam, play the guitar and DIY stuff.

Cook more vegetarian food and grow more chilies.

